My daughter and I have
stopped communicating.
I have a daughter
who is a junior in college.
(Questioner) My earnest wish is to
communicate with my daughter.
I don't believe that
I have been that harsh toward her.
I have been searching for
what I might have done wrong.
One thing comes to mind.
When she was a senior in high school,
she would leave the light
on while studying late at night.
(Audience Laughter)
(Sunim) Light should be off when sleeping,
How can she study with light off?
Exactly. I was proud of her
studying late into the night.
But when I entered her room,
I found her sleeping always.
At first, I found her sleeping at her desk.
Then later she was
sleeping lying down altogether.
I have never told her to study.
"Turn the light off when you sleep!"
was all I said.
But she never followed my request.
I couldn't let that continue
so I scolded her once.
"I don't want you to study.
Just turn the light off and go to sleep."
"I worry about your health.”
I believe that was all I said.
but since then,
she stopped talking to me.
So, I thought about the reason.
It's true that when she was young,
I was busy with my work
and I did not spend much time with her.
She sent me notes to ask me
what she wanted to know.
I realized that she was doing that
because there was
no communication between us.
So, I decided to write letters to her.
So when she was a freshman,
I wrote to her.
But even after 3-4 letters,
there was no reply.
I figured she would come to me
when she needed money.
But instead of coming to me, she would
go to her mom to ask for money.
This is my concern.
What would happen to me if she gets
married while our relationship is poor?
I worry if she could have a
decent marriage.
Today, I have my college friend
next to me.
I am here because of this friend.
He has two daughters.
Whenever I visit him at his home,
I find his daughters are really sweet.
He has good conversations
with his daughter's boyfriend.
I am very envious of that.
I feel that I have done everything I can.
How can I communicate with
my daughter?
Please teach me.
Whose daughter is she?
(Questioner) She is mine.
You gave her birth and you raised her.
Yet you are asking me what to do
when I haven't even met her?
(Laughter)
(Audience Laughter)
Whom should I ask then?
(Sunim) Earlier, you mentioned
the turning off the light.
That is not the reason.
But let's talk about it.
Without making an issue
of her falling asleep,
you told her to turn the light off
when she goes to sleep.
That was all you said.
It may seem obvious to you.
But this shows your lack of
understanding about your daughter.
Because,
she had no intention to sleep.
She would turn the light off
if she were going to sleep.
She felt that she should not sleep.
Do you understand?
She was under pressure to study,
but her mind and body were tired.
She was so tired,
she would fall asleep at her desk.
Turning off the light means
having the intention to sleep.
She had no intention to sleep.
She was trying to study somehow.
But her mind and body
just failed her.
So, she would fall asleep at the desk.
Even when she lay down,
she didn’t intend to sleep.
She thought she would lie down a bit
and get up to study.
You could have seen that
she was under pressure to study.
As a father, when you saw her asleep,
"You must be tired. Get some sleep.
I'll wake you up later"
Thinking like this, you could lay her
in bed, turning the light off for her.
Or when you found her in bed,
you could have thought,
"She must be really tired."
Then you just turn the light off.
There would be no problem.
You only keep your point of view
without considering her situation at all.
Your wife must be quite frustrated
living with a man like you
(Audience Laughter)
(Sunim) You may think
'I work and I provide all this for you.
So what are you complaining about?'
You may think like this but
it's different for women.
If your wife had a job and you had to
put on an apron to cook, do the dishes,
and take care of kids
Would you be able to handle it all?
I don't think so.
(Sunim) If she came home late,
you would throw a fit.
You would accuse her
of some misconduct.
But people are generally like this.
When you do some work,
you only see the outward appearances.
If the worth of work is
measured by numbers,
people can be satisfied
with their work.
But there is nothing to show for
cleaning, doing the dishes
and taking care of kids,
even though it's time consuming
and hard work.
You can't measure it.
You cook, but it's gone
after you eat it.
You do the dishes,
but you have the same number of dishes.
They don't increase in numbers.
You clean the house,
but it's always the same.
So the husband
comes home and says
'What do you do all day?
Have you done anything?'
He can measure his work
by his monthly salary
...$1000, $2000, $3000..
or he gets promoted,
or something.
That's why
communication is difficult.
So, judging from the way
you deal with your daughter,
I can see your wife must be
rather frustrated with you.
Not that you have done
something really bad.
But she feels frustrated because
you don't acknowledge her.
Frustrated and disappointed
by the husband,
she would end up
complaining to the child
without any intention.
"oh, it's difficult to live
with your father,"
"how can I go on like this?"
(Sunim) Even in passing
she would say this sort of things.
Your daughter hears these
once, twice, 3 times
while she grows up.
This would make her to think
'My dad is the problem.'
There won't be any
emotional exchanges with her dad.
She would keep some
emotional distance from her dad
Because she receives money from him
or has to greet him.
Then this incident happens
and the emotional scars surface
from her subconscious
and she feels
'I don't want to deal with him'
When her notes came,
you should have
also written short notes.
"Thanks for asking
even through the note,'
That would have been fine.
But your long letters
bothered her further.
That is why she is communicating
through her mom.
You need to make a choice.
If you think your daughter is the problem,
you can reprimand and correct her.
If not, you need to change yourself.
If she is the problem,
correcting her is simple.
I don't know how effective this would be.
How about this?
Cut her allowance off completely
if she doesn't ask you directly.
Even if she asks
through your wife,
you can say,
" Ask me directly if you need money!"
Ask your wife’s cooperation
to correct her behavior.
" you don't appreciate my support"
"now that you are over 20 years old,
I can't support you any longer"
"if you want my help,
ask me directly or be on your own."
You need to cut the
emotional ties like this.
It's not a crime because
she is over 20 years old.
You've done your job.
You can't do this to a minor.
It is against the law.
After the age of 20
You have no legal, ethical,
or moral obligations to her.
You can cut the
parental ties with her.
You relate to her as an
individual, one on one.
You may do that.
It's not bad.
That can be good.
Or, if you want to have a
better relationship with her
the first thing
you need to do is to
offer repentance prayers
to your wife.
Leave aside the problem
with your daughter.
You need to do 108 bows every morning
as you repent toward your wife.
"Honey, It must have been hard for you to
put up with me all these years.
I am sorry. I was willful
and wasn't aware of your pain."
When you can communicate
with your wife with ease,
you will see some changes
in your daughter.
You should not force
your daughter to communicate.
It's as if when you like someone
and you force your love on her
by hugging her
then it becomes a
harassment not love.
You would be harassing your daughter
if you demand her to talk to you.
It's coercing the other person.
If you want communication,
you can't demand it.
Demanding is not
communicating.
And don't be impatient.
Just accept her
when she approaches you.
You are filled with desire
to approach her.
It's not that your daughter
wishes to communicate
and you are refusing her.
You are desperate to talk to her
even though
she doesn't want to.
That is a demand.
Only respond to her
when she asks, whatever she asks.
And talk about things
that she enjoys.
Right now, you are trying to
make her follow your pace.
So, she is rejecting it.
It may work with your wife,
but not with your daughter.
Your wife is stuck with you
because of money or what not,
but your daughter can get
what she needs from her mom.
Even though,
it ultimately comes from you,
you daughter wants
no business with you.
She can get it from her mom.
A child knows that
water comes from a faucet.
So she just turns the faucet on.
So, how should you
solve this problem?
First, communicate
with your wife.
Then you can communicate
with your daughter.
(Questioner)
I understand. Thank you.
(Sunim Laughter)
(Apploause)